

Hussein Mahfouz

■ Date of birth: 26/02/1987 ■ Nationality: Egyptian ■ Address: Cairo, Egypt

Phone number: +201000661156

Email address: Hussein.Mahfouz@Live.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/husseinmahfouz/



Profile

With 14 years of experience in the Information Technology (learnt the industry from the ground up) I believe that i poses leadership, technical, administrative as well as operational skills. With a strong focus on the customers' needs and with an ability of understanding and learning the requirements and needs of prospects.



Work experience

07/2018 – present Cairo, Egypt

Software Presales Manager Global Brands (GBG)

- Promoting Microsoft modern technology cloud solutions for business needs fulfillment and working closely and collaboratively with customers to devise effective solutions, understand and capture requirements.
- Actively driving and managing the Pre-Sales process with direct and channel customers.
- Manage and write responses for RFP / RFI processes and responses that involve multiple service lines to solve complex business problems for clients.
- Putting together business cases for the sales teams to support their proposals.
- Providing Functional and Technical solutions to new & existing corporate customers on Software Solutions also Provide ongoing support for customers during implementation.

02/2017 - 06/2018 Cairo, Egypt

Professional Services Team Leader Global Brands (GBG)

- Execute technical engagements Proof-Of-Concept & Architecture designs of Microsoft's Infrastructure or Cloud Solutions that helps in meeting the customer's requirements.
- Architecting & Implementing and Administering Microsoft Azure Cloud Solutions (IaaS, PaaS, SaaS)
- Deal with escalations and high business impact cases and responsible for delivering weekly/monthly/yearly reports for the management.
- Providing coaching and mentorship to lead my colleague from a technical point of view and to be a point of reference for technical challenges.
- Coordinate team activities with lateral teams across disciplines and Oversee the quality of deliveries and ensure conformance to processes and practices.

Work experience

03/2016 - 02/2017 Cairo, Egypt

Microsoft Technical Lead Global Brands (GBG)

- Responsible to ensure the Operations, Maintenance and Support of the Cloud infrastructure platforms as well as to support the definition of detailed requirements, create designs and plans, and ensures implementation of highavailability Cloud services and System Center infrastructure solutions.
- Responsible to monitor and report on service health as well as design and implement disaster recovery and security solutions. Also plan upgrades, migrations, and deployments.
- Fully responsible for ensuring high-availability and service stability as well as for service enhancements.
- End-to-End responsible for the Service Delivery to Enterprise customers. Manages technical deliverable and projects, ensuring documentation, configuration management and knowledge transfer to supporting teams.

06/2011 - 02/2016 Cairo, Egypt

Senior Microsoft Systems Engineer Summit Technology Solutions (STS)

- Represent STS as a primary technical contact on projects as assigned.
- Install, Configure, Monitoring and Managing Microsoft Solutions.
- Weekly follow up support and maintenance contracts including systems health and performance check onsite & remote Support.

06/2010 - 05/2011 Cairo, Egypt

Tech Support Team Leader Orascom Telecom Holding (OTH)

- Support employees with SLA respond 2 minutes; troubleshoot their problems on-site or via phone.
- Manage equipment inventory and responsible for IT Assets.

11/2008 – 06/2010 Cairo, Egypt

IT Support Specialist BDO

• Install and repair, maintain company desktop and laptop computers software\hardware, Printers.

03/2007 – 10/2007 Cairo, Egypt

ISP Technical Support ECCO Outsourcing

 Act as a first line of support to all TE-Data Egypt internet users' inquiries (technical / billing).



Education

2004 – 2007 Cairo, Egypt

Bachelor of Information Systems Future Academy

2000 – 2003 Cairo, Egypt **Secondary Class - Literary El-Koba Military High School**

Language Skills

- LANGUAGES

English PROFESSIONAL

Arabic **NATIVE**

Certificates

ITIL v3 in IT Service Management EXIN

Certified Technical Sales Professional Veeam Software

Certified Licensing Fundamentals Microsoft

MCSE: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure Microsoft

MCSA: Office 365

Microsoft

MCSA: Cloud Platform

Microsoft

MCSA: Windows Server 2008, 2012 and 2016

Microsoft

MCTS: Microsoft SharePoint

Microsoft

MCTS: Microsoft System Center

Microsoft

MCTS: Windows Vista, 7 and Office

Microsoft

